Preliminary Inventory to the William J. Platt Papers, 1946-1997.
Hoover Institution Archives
William J. Platt Papers,
1946-1997.
80008
Platt, William J. (William James), 1916-
12 manuscript boxes (4.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Speeches and writings, reports, memoranda, bulletins, serial issues, and other printed matter, relating to international educational development, especially educational activities of Unesco.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1980
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Unesco.; Education.; International education.
Container List
- Speeches and writings by William J. Platt, 1946-1988 (Box 1.)
- Bellagio meetings (Box 2.)
- China
- Copenhagen Seminar, 1974
- "Educational Television in Three Developing Areas"
- International Institute for Educational Planning
- Mathematics Education Conference, Urbana, Illinois, 1976
- Missions
- United Nations
- UNESCO - Memoranda by William J. Platt, 1970-75 (Box 3.)
- UNESCO - Educational reform, 1977
- UNICEF
- U.S.S.R.
- Memoranda and reports (unpublished) (Box 4.)
- Memoranda and reports (unpublished) (Box 5.)
- Issuances of the U.S. Agency for International Development
- Issuances of the Stanford Research Institute (Box 6.)
- Issuances of the Stanford Research Institute (Box 7.)
- Issuances of the Stanford International Development Education Center
- Issuances of UNESCO (Box 8.)
- Issuances of the UNESCO International Institute for Educational Planning (Box 9.)
- Miscellaneous reports and serial issues (mostly published)
- Miscellaneous reports and serial issues (mostly published) (Box 10-12.)